欢迎光临Air House77超级影院！！！
Welcome to Air House Cinemas
请爱护包厢设施环境卫生
Please take care of the environmental hygiene of the room
如有损坏，照价赔偿
In case of damage ，Compensation at cost
请保管好您的随身物品，以免丢失
Please keep your belongings，So as not to lose
Air House77超级影院祝您观影愉快,每天都有好心情
Air House Cinemas wish you have a nice day!
从前有一个女巫
Once upon a time there was a witch
他们住在我们世界的边界
who lived at the border of our world
以及死者的世界
and the world of the dead.
她曾经绑架过孩子
She used to abduct children
派她忠实的仆人
by sending her faithful servants the Navs
半鸟半人无情
merciless half-birds, half-humans.
纳夫们把孩子们引到女巫的巢穴里
The Navs lured the children to the witch's den
在那里她吞噬了他们的灵魂
where she devoured their souls.
父母忘记了他们的孩子
Parents forgot their children
好像他们从未存在过
as if they had never existed.
但是一个有着纯洁和光明灵魂的男孩
But one boy with a pure and bright soul
成功击败了一个女巫
managed to defeat a witch
把她囚禁在死者的世界里
and imprison her in the world of the dead.
然而 女巫并没有放弃
However, the witch didn't give up.
她开始找人
She began to look for someone
谁会帮她回来
who would help her get back.
一个纯洁的灵魂会比黑夜更黑暗的人
Someone whose pure soul would become darker than night,
谁能跨越世界的边界
who can cross the borders of the worlds.
某人
Someone
他已经死过一次了
who has already been dead once.
时间过去了
Time passed,
对那个女巫的记忆只停留在童话里
and the memories of that witch remained only in fairy tales.
人们叫她
People call her...
-埃戈尔 你为什么这么晚？
- Egor, why are you so late?
一切都好吗？
Is everything okay?
-妈妈 我们回家吧
- Mom, let's go home.
-你长大这么快 宝贝
- You've grown up so fast, baby.
还记得我们以前是怎么玩的吗？
Remember how we used to play?
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
这很重要
This is very important.
你会帮我回来的 -从哪里回来？
You'll help me return. - Return from where?
妈妈 你是
Mom, you are...
-你是说 我死了？
- You mean, I'm dead?
-埃戈尔 你一直在尖叫
- Egor, you've been screaming.
又是一场噩梦吗？
Was it another nightmare?
-有人教你敲门吗？
- Has anybody taught you to knock?
-你睡前看什么废话？
- What nonsense do you read before bed?
这就是你做噩梦的原因 -嘿 别碰它！
That's why you have nightmares. - Hey, don't touch it!
-宝贝 我也不喜欢搬家
- Baby, I don't like moving houses either.
-朱莉娅 我不是婴儿
- Julia, I'm not a baby.
-你觉得我不知道当一个新孩子是什么感觉吗？
- Do you think I don't know what it's like to be a new kid?
新学校 新朋友
New school, new friends...
-你得走了
- You have to go.
你女儿醒了
Your daughter is awake.
-过来
- Come here.
在这里 把它放在那边
Here. Put it over there.
-好吧
- Okay.
-把它放好 这样就不会吸引眼球了 好吗？
- Just put it so it doesn't catch the eye, okay?
-你要请保姆吗？
- Are you hiring a nanny?
-是的
- Yes.
-但你不想 -有时候你不得不让步
- But you didn't want to. - Sometimes you have to concede.
我们会照看保姆的
We'll keep an eye on the nanny.
-如果她不工作为什么需要保姆？
- Why does she need a nanny if she doesn't work?
-你还不够成熟 不能批评你妈妈
- You're not mature enough to criticize your mother.
-她不是我妈妈
- She's not my mother.
-坐下来吃早饭 我为你做的
- Sit down and have breakfast. I've made it for you.
-我在学校吃饭
- I'll eat at school.
-又怎么了？
- What's wrong again?
-过渡年龄
- Transitional age.
-你不觉得已经有一段时间了吗？
- Don't you think it's been a while?
-哎哟！-怎么了？
- Ouch! - What happened?
-我被电死了
- I've got electrocuted.
这是什么样的早晨？
What kind of morning is this?
太好了 现在不行了
Great, now it's not working.
-亚历克西 我再也受不了了
- Alexey, I can't take it anymore.
我受不了
I can't handle it.
-我们一直在努力 这次我们也会成功的
- We've always managed. We'll make it this time too.
-伊娃 今天什么时候上音乐课？
- Eva, what time is the music lesson today?
-你的音乐导师晚上8点会等你
- Your music tutor will be waiting for you at 8 pm.
-谢谢你 伊娃
- Thank you, Eva.
-嘿 你在嘀咕什么？
- Hey, what are you muttering?
-你要去哪里？他问了你一个问题
- Where are you going? He asked you a question.
-和普通人说话有失你的身份吗？
- Is it beneath you to speak to normal people?
-正常情况下你是指你自己？
- By normal you mean yourself?
把电话给我
Give me the phone.
-礼貌地问 也许我会的
- Ask politely. Maybe I will.
你疯了吗 怪物？
Are you out of your mind, freak?
你在看什么？把它给我！
What are you staring at? Give it to me!
-他是个弱智！
- He's retarded!
-别傻了 -把电话给他
- Don't be stupid. - Give him the phone.
-给你
- Here you are.
-我本来可以处理的
- I could have handled this.
-你从哪里冒出来的？
- Where have you sprung from?
-在这里 惩罚你自己
- Here, punish yourself.
-你太麻烦了！
- You're so in trouble!
-你生气了吗？
- Have you pissed yourself?
-去找你妈妈 娘娘腔
- Run to your mother, sissy.
-起来 懦夫！
- Get up, coward!
-放开他
- Get off him.
-嘿 别闹了！
- Hey, break it up!
-我们离开这里 伙计们！
- Let's get out of here, guys!
-再见 怪胎
- See you soon, freaks.
-嘿！等等
- Hey! Wait up.
你好
Hi.
-你没必要
- You didn't have to.
-邻居应该互相帮助
- Neighbours should help each other.
真 的！
Wow!
它真的是你的吗？
Is it really yours?
-是的 -那你为什么不用呢？
- It is. - Then why didn't you use it?
-因为你挡了路
- Because you got in the way.
-等等！
- Wait!
你的名字叫什么？
What is your name?
-有些人叫我达什卡
- Some people call me Dashka.
-其他人呢？-丹尼娅！
- And others? - Daniya!
-我以为我们有协议没有男朋友
- I thought we had an agreement no boyfriends.
现在回家吧 -是的 妈妈
Now go home. - Yes, mom.
-顺便说一下 我叫埃戈尔
- By the way, my name is Egor.
丹尼娅
Daniya...
-她可以从扶手椅上摔下来
- She can fall down the armchair.
把她单独放在那里不是个好主意
It's not a good idea to put her there on her own.
-我没把她放在那里
- I didn't put her there.
-埃戈尔 你为什么把她放在那里？
- Egor, why did you put her there?
你还有别的事可做吗？
Have you got nothing better to do?
-我进来的时候她就在那儿 -够了
- She was there when I came in. - That's enough.
你们已经自我介绍了吗？
Have you already introduced yourselves?
这是我们的保姆塔蒂安娜 她会照顾瓦利亚的
This is our nanny Tatiana. She's going to look after Varya.
你也是 当她在做的时候
And you too, while she's at it.
-嗯 我不需要照顾
- Well, I don't need looking after.
-埃戈尔 别这么粗鲁
- Egor, don't be rude.
他会习惯我在身边的
He'll get used to me being around.
嘘 嘘
Hush, hush...
我总是想办法和孩子们沟通
I always find a way to get through to kids.
总是这样
Always.
你妈妈不是告诉过你监视别人是不礼貌的吗？
Didn't your mother tell you it's rude to spy on people?
-她不是我妈妈 -你觉得你很特别吗？
- She's not my mother. - You think you're special?
你觉得你能感觉到别人看不到的东西？
You think you sense things that other people don't?
你会长大的 如果你长大了 那就是
You'll grow out of it. If you ever grow up, that is...
有人在家吗？
Anyone home?
-你好 -你好
- Hello. - Hello.
-嗯   朱莉娅在哪？
- Umm... Where's Julia?
-她和那个小家伙在一起
- She's with the little one while
我在打扫卫生
I'm doing some cleaning.
-一切都好吗？-一切都很好
- Is everything alright? - Everything's wonderful.
-对不起 我们以前从来没有真正的保姆
- I'm sorry, we never really had a nanny before.
-一切都是第一次 亚历克西
- There's a first time for everything, Alexey.
-怎么了？
- What's up?
学校怎么样？你交过朋友吗？
How is school? Have you made any friends?
-是的 -是吗？脸怎么了？
- Yeah. - Yeah? What's with the face?
-我摔倒了
- I fell down.
-摔倒了？真正的男人不能摔倒
- Fell down? Real men mustn't fall down.
真正的男人必须自立
Real men must stand on their own two feet.
-爸爸 这是陈词滥调
- Dad, it's a cliché.
-真正的男人必须保护他们所爱的人
- Real men must protect those who are dear to them.
-你呢？你保护你所爱的人吗？
- What about you? Do you protect those who are dear to you?
-当然
- Of course.
-但在你看来 我们家有个厚颜无耻的保姆是正常的吗？
- But a brazen-faced nanny in our house seems normal to you?
-让我自己决定
- Let me decide myself
在我家里什么是正常的 好吗？
what is normal in my house, okay?
-很好！
- Fine!
-回来吧 我们还没完呢
- Come back here, we're not finished.
埃戈尔！
Egor!
停下来！你听见了吗？
Cut it! Do you hear me?
你母亲去世时 我几乎失去理智
When your mother died, I almost lost my mind.
但你活下来了 所以别抱怨了 好吗？
But you survived. So stop whining, okay?
-埃戈尔！埃戈尔！
- Egor! Egor!
嘿 伙计 把球还给我
Hey man, give the ball back.
走吧
Let's go.
-哎哟！
- Ouch!
-我发誓我看见她了！
- I swear I saw her!
-我再给你看一遍
- Let me show you again.
给 看
Here, look.
里面什么都没有
There's nothing in there.
-那是因为你睡觉前经常看篮球
- That's because you watch a lot of basketball before bed.
再加上这一点他的焦虑
Add this to his anxiety.
-另一方面 你不必担心
- You, on the other hand, have no worries.
-住手！
- Stop it!
-妈妈会相信我的
- Mom would believe me.
-朱莉娅 你能给我们点时间吗？
- Julia, can you give us a moment, please?
埃戈尔 听着 我厌倦了你的戏剧
Egor, listen. I'm sick and tired of your drama.
我明白 但妈妈死了
I get it, but mother is dead.
是时候忘掉它了
It's time to forget about it.
-忘了？
- Forget?
保护你所爱的人 还是忘记？
Protect those who are dear to you, or forget?
很容易忘记 这是真的
It's easier to forget, that's true.
好像她从未存在过
As if she's never existed.
-很好
- Fine.
如果我们不能以朋友的身份解决这个问题
If we can't settle this as friends,
我们会努力的
we'll do it the hard way.
-你到底怎么了？
- What the hell is wrong with you?
谁来赔偿损坏的货物？我呢？
Who's going to pay for the damaged goods? Me?
我一辈子都在为你付钱
I've been paying for you my whole life.
你从政府那里得到钱
You get money from state.
-什么？
- What?
他们不给我钱！
They pay me nothing!
没人需要你
Nobody needs you.
不管是国家还是你母亲
Neither the state nor your mother.
我才是受苦的人
I'm the one suffering.
是的 对
Yeah, right.
你受了很多苦
You suffered a lot...
那是用来卸货的
That's for unloading.
你还没赚到
You haven't earned it yet.
现在去你的白痴朋友那里
Now run to your moron friends.
十点以前不要回家 我会有客人的
Don't come home before 10. I'll be having guests.
-这是我的薪水 婊子
- This is my salary, bitch.
你在看什么？你不是在马戏团
What are you staring at? You're not in a circus.
我们有事要做
We have some business to do.
根据维基百科
According to Wikipedia,
克劳德·德彪西是法国作曲家
Claude Debussy is a French composer,
主要代表
a leading representative of...
-你知道上网很久了吗
- Did you know that being online for a long time
让你与现实世界失去联系
makes you lose touch with the real world.
-什么？
- What?
糟糕的尝试 -等等！
Bad try. - Hold on!
你为什么总是在某处跑？
Why are you always running somewhere?
-我没有跑 我在走
- I'm not running, I'm walking.
-你为什么是认真的？
- Why are you serious?
如果你变得更友好 也许你会有一些朋友
If you become friendlier, maybe you'll have some friends.
-如果你学会讲好笑话 你也会有一些
- You'll also have some if you learn to make good jokes.
现在快跑
Now run.
-嘿！快过来！-快点！
- Hey! Come here now! - Hurry!
-住手！别动！
- Stop! Freeze!
-他们来了！他们往那边走了！
- There they are! They went that way!
-住手！我来抓你！
- Stop! I'll get you!
伙计们 帮帮我！
Guys, help me!
-哇   这是什么地方？
- Wow... What's this place?
-我不知道
- I don't know.
-快来 快！
- Come, quick!
-儿童不允许进入森林
- Children aren't allowed in the forest.
如果我再见到你 我会把你的头撕下来
If I see you again, I'll tear your head off.
-你把裤子撕碎脱了吗？
- Have you shat your pants and took off?
-妈妈告诉我他是个文物猎人
- Mother told me he's an artifact hunter.
他在森林里寻找二战武器
He looks for WWII weapons in the forest.
他还杀了他的妻子
He also killed his wife.
最好不要惹他
It's better not to mess with him.
-武器 哈？
- Weapons, huh?
-这是什么？
- What is this?
-它看起来像个火炉
- It looks like a furnace.
我奶奶常说这些是用来烧人的
My grandma used to say these were used for burning people...
……活着
...alive.
她还说
She also said that after their
他们的灵魂就在附近
death their souls stayed somewhere near.
有时他们会悄悄地叫你的名字
Sometimes they can quietly call you by your name.
但如果你转身 他们会把你的脸拿走
But if you turn around, they'll take your face away.
埃戈尔 帮我离开这里
Egor, help me get out of here.
-你听到了吗？-没有
- Did you hear it? - No.
-嘘！抓住你了 我只是开玩笑
- Boo! Got you. I'm just kidding.
瓦里亚？瓦里亚？
Varya? Varya?
-嘿！-我猜是回声
- Hey! - I guess it's echo.
-回音！-看到了吗？里面什么都没有
- Echo! - See? There's nothing in there.
有什么？
What is there?
-我们该回家了
- We should get home.
订阅服务器当前为
The subscriber is currently
无法到达 请稍后再试
not reachable. Please try again later.
-爸爸？朱莉娅？
- Dad? Julia?
-也许你的相机坏了 -也许吧
- Maybe your camera's acting up. - Maybe.
这已经发生过一次了
This has already happened once.
-她太小了
- She's so tiny.
-太奇怪了
- That's weird.
我可以留下来和你一起等吗？
Shall I stay and wait here with you?
你的音乐家教课10分钟后开始
Your lesson with a music tutor starts in 10 minutes.
-没关系 我会没事的
- That's okay, I'll be fine.
谢谢您
Thank you.
-瓦里亚失踪了 她所有的东西都不见了
- Varya's gone missing. And all her stuff is gone.
谁去了哪里？坐下来吃早饭
Who's gone where? Sit down and have breakfast.
-埃戈尔 我们还没有带来
- Egor, we still haven't brought
所有旧公寓里的东西
all the stuff from the old apartment.
坐下 怎么了
Sit. What's the matter?
-你女儿失踪了 她带走了她
- Your daughter has gone missing. She took her.
-这不再有趣了 坐下来冷静一下
- This isn't funny anymore. Sit down and chill out.
-埃戈尔 你在干什么？
- Egor, what are you doing?
-来 看！
- Here, look!
-哇哦 正确的 -埃戈尔
- Wow. Right. - Egor...
-什么？我们得做点什么 你们这些白痴！
- What? We have to do something, you idiots!
-冷静点
- Calm down.
-你忘了她就像你忘了我妈妈一样！
- You've forgotten her just like you forgot my mom!
-亚历克西！亚历克西 不要！-过来
- Alexey! Alexey, don't! - Come over here.
-放开我！别管我！
- Let me go! Leave me alone!
-住手！亚历克西 你在干什么？
- Stop! Alexey, what are you doing?
住手！-别插手！
Stop it! - Stay out of it!
-够了！
- Enough!
-呆在这里想一想
- Stay here and think for a while.
如果你再这样做
If you do this again,
我要把你赶出这所房子
I'll throw you out of this house.
嘿 我们能谈谈吗？我需要你的帮助
Hey, can we talk? I need your help.
我20分钟后在操场上见
I'll meet you on the playground in 20 minutes.
-你想去哪里？
- Where do you think you're going?
-我很快就回来 -你在和那个男孩见面吗？
- I'll be back soon. - Are you meeting that boy?
-他很好
- He's nice.
-一个女孩曾经和一个好男孩私奔了
- One girl once ran away with a nice boy.
他不断地告诉她她有多漂亮
He kept on telling her how beautiful she was.
但最后 女孩留下了一个女儿
But in the end, the girl was left with a daughter
还有一架没人要的旧钢琴
and an old piano that nobody wants.
美丽是危险的
Beauty is dangerous.
永远不要相信男人
Never trust men.
-妈妈
- Mom...
-我是不是白给家教钱？
- Am I paying the tutor for nothing?
开始练习吧
Get to your exercises.
-我希望我对他不是太苛刻？
- I hope I wasn't too hard on him?
-你什么都做对了
- You did everything right.
孩子们应该知道他们的位置
Kids should know their place.
他是个聪明的孩子 为什么他会幻想出一个虚构的妹妹？
He's a smart kid. Why would he dream up an imaginary sister?
-我不知道 也许他想要个小妹妹？
- I don't know. Maybe he wants a little sister?
-现在不行 亚历克西
- Not now, Alexey.
你说要把他赶出去是认真的吗？
Were you serious when you said you would throw him out?
-别插手 好吗？
- Keep out of it, okay?
孩子们应该知道他们的位置
Kids should know their place.
-我不能再玩了 我累了
- I can't play anymore, I'm tired.
-别让我失望
- Don't let me down.
你很快就会到的
You'll get there soon.
妈妈？
Mom?
如果你敢打开它 你会后悔的
If you dare open it, you'll seriously regret this.
大沙！大沙！
Dasha! Dasha!
大沙 等等！大沙！
Dasha, wait! Dasha!
怎么了
What's the matter?
大沙！请稍等
Dasha! Wait, please.
-她会回来的 她会回来的
- She'll come back. She'll come back.
-醒醒！醒醒！
- Wake up! Wake up!
-她会回来的！-大沙 醒醒！
- She'll come back! - Dasha, wake up!
丹尼娅！
Daniya!
-埃戈尔？发生了什么事？
- Egor? What has happened?
-她带走了瓦里亚   -你在说谁？
- She took Varya... - Who are you talking about?
-你也不记得她了
- You don't remember her either.
-你能听见吗？
- Can you hear?
-没有
- No.
-太安静了
- It's so quiet.
嘿 白痴 我们有事要做
Hey, moron. We have some business to do.
-进去看看有没有人
- Just go inside and look whether there is somebody.
然后打开门 你明白吗？
And then open the door. Do you understand?
-你为什么需要这个罐子？
- Why do you need the can?
-你觉得你是最聪明的 嗯？
- You think you're the smartest, huh?
-别碰我
- Don't touch me.
-嘿 放开她！-别干涉他们的事
- Hey, get off her! - Don't meddle in their affairs.
真 的
Wow.
-现在呢？
- Now what?
你觉得你这么勇敢？-把刀收起来
You think you're so brave? - Put the knife away.
我去
I'll go.
伙计们 你们得看看这个
Guys, you have to see this.
他一直在监视我们吗？
Has he been spying on us?
疯狂的疯子
Freaking maniac...
伊娃 报警
Eva, call the police.
-你疯了吗？
- Have you lost your mind?
我们会因为闯入一所房子而被捕
We'll get arrested for breaking into a house.
-这是我们的保姆 -我的音乐导师
- This is our nanny. - My music tutor.
-她很可爱
- She's cute.
别担心 那是米莎
Don't sweat it, that's Misha.
你好
Hi there.
又是你
It's you again.
我警告过你
I have warned you...
我本来可以处理的
I could've handled it.
-那是谁？
- Who's that?
你认识她吗？
Do you know her?
-关掉灯 孩子们
- Turn off the lights, kids.
-你聋了吗？我们问了你一个问题 回答
- Are you deaf? We asked you a question. Answer it.
-这是我妻子
- This is my wife.
我们女儿失踪后她就死了
She died after our daughter had disappeared.
-死了？他杀了她！每个人都知道
- Died? He killed her! Everyone knows that.
-你女儿失踪了吗？
- Has your daughter gone missing?
-孩子们已经消失了一段时间了 但是没有人
- Kids have been disappearing for a while now, but nobody
记得他们
remembers them.
似乎连他们的父母都不需要
It seems that even their parents don't need them.
-告诉我们你知道的一切
- Tell us everything you know.
有一天 我醒来时有一种感觉 我失去了一些东西
One day I woke up with a feeling that I lost something.
重要的事 但我不记得是什么了
Something important. But I couldn't remember what it was.
只有一支蜡烛在燃烧
There was only a candle burning.
每当我看着蜡烛
Whenever I looked at the candle,
我不知怎的想起了
I somehow recalled this old
我差点忘了的梦
dream that I had almost forgotten.
关于我孩子的梦
A dream about my baby.
电-这就是我为什么知道邪恶来到这个城市的原因
Electricity — that's how I knew that evil came to the city.
每次有孩子失踪
Every time some child disappeared,
该地区曾停电
there had been power cuts in the area.
我开始跟踪孩子们并给他们拍照
I began following the kids and taking pictures of them.
每当孩子突然从照片上消失
Whenever the kid suddenly disappeared from the photo,
这意味着每个人都忘记了他
it meant everyone has forgotten him.
这就是我如何追踪失踪儿童的方法
That's how I could track how many children were missing.
多年来我一直在努力寻找我的女儿
I've been trying to find my daughter for many years.
但我没有成功
But I haven't succeeded.
我在这里定居 在森林里
I settled here, in the forest.
但我在这里什么也没找到
But I haven't found anything here
除了红线
except red threads.
-但是谁需要忘记孩子呢？
- But who needs children to be forgotten?
谁把他们带走了？
Who's been taking them away?
-他们信任的人
- Someone they trust.
能轻易进入房子的人
Someone who can easily enter the house.
-你是说你妻子来接你吗
- Are you saying that your wife comes and takes
孩子们去森林？
children to the forest?
-那不是她
- That's not her.
-伊娃 你听说了吗？
- Eva, have you heard?
-女人 偷 孩子们 森林
- Woman. Steal. Children. Forest.
你的要求符合一个斯拉夫恶魔
Your request matches a Slavic demon
住在
who lives on the border between
活着的和死去的-雅加爸爸
the living and the dead - Baba Yaga.
-伊娃 你是认真的吗？
- Eva, are you serious?
-没什么可取笑的
- There's nothing to make fun of.
-这个地方怎么样？你去过那里吗？
- What about this place? Have you been there?
-很多次
- Many times.
那是一个废弃的发电站
That's an abandoned power station.
你在那里什么也找不到 它不起作用
You won't find anything there. It doesn't work.
-相信我 是的
- Believe me, it does.
-我们应该把他解开
- We should have untied him.
-我们会在回来的路上做的
- We'll do it on our way back.
嘿！你真的相信他吗？
Hey! Do you really believe him?
这家伙显然疯了 但你看起来很正常
This guy's obviously crazy, but you seem sane.
-你想要什么？我要去
- What do you want? I'm going to
把我妹妹找回来 明白吗？
get my sister back, do you understand?
我们根本不需要你
We don't need you at all.
你想走就走
You can go if you want.
-我也不需要你
- I don't need you either.
-好吧 我们走吧
- Okay, let's go.
你要来吗？
Are you coming?
你会忘记一切的
You'll forget everything.
-这些绳子是从哪里来的？
- Where do these ropes come from?
-他们通向小屋
- They lead to the hut.
-哇 太棒了 -嘘！
- Wow, that's huge. - Shhh!
-别紧张！
- Take it easy!
-它看起来太旧了
- It looks so old.
-我会很快的
- I'll be quick.
-小心点
- Be careful.
-别被电死 蠢货
- Don't get electrocuted, dumbass.
-伙计们 我在这里发现了一些奇怪的东西！
- Guys, I found something strange in here!
-埃戈尔！
- Egor!
-别进去 -懦夫！
- Don't go in there. - Coward!
-我好久没见你了
- I haven't seen you for quite some time.
-我有事要做 你想我了吗？
- I've had some business to do. Did you miss me?
-我不想你再离开了
- I don't want you to leave ever again.
-你怎么能放他走？
- How could you let him go?
当男孩回来的时候
When the boy comes back...
-我要杀了他
- I'll kill him.
-我会永远和你在一起
- And I'll be always with you.
-你没事吧？
- Are you okay?
-怎么了？
- What happened?
-我真的不知道 我昏过去了
- I actually don't know. I blacked out.
-我也是
- Me too.
-起来
- Get up.
-嘿！
- Hey!
我以为你是来找你妹妹的
I thought you came here to look for your sister.
真的有姐妹吗？
Is there actually a sister?
-停下来 安东
- Cut it out, Anton.
-也许没有姐妹？
- Maybe there isn't any sister?
-你嫉妒吗？
- Are you jealous?
-你为什么带她去森林？
- Why did you take her to the forest?
你想有点隐私吗？
Did you want to have some privacy?
-这不关你的事
- It's none of your business.
不是我拖她来的
I didn't drag either you or her here.
-但你让我们跟着你
- But you asked us to follow you.
你知道吗？
You know what?
你们两个我都烦透了
I'm sick of you both.
-大沙！
- Dasha!
大沙！
Dasha!
等待！
Wait!
-没有姐妹 没有女朋友 是吗？
- No sister, no girlfriend, huh?
-住手！
- Stop it!
去你的！你真是精神病
Screw you! You're really mental.
-瓦里亚！
- Varya!
-妈妈！你在家吗？
- Mom! Are you at home?
妈妈？
Mom?
-爸爸 你在家吗？
- Dad, are you at home?
-嘿！
- Hey!
-朱莉娅 看
- Julia, look.
朱莉娅！
Julia!
朱莉娅！朱莉娅！
Julia! Julia!
-当   男孩…会来
- When... The boy...will come...
-亚历克西 怎么了？
- Alexey, what's wrong?
-伊娃 请跟我谈谈
- Eva, please talk to me.
-晚上好！你好吗？
- Good evening! How are you?
-我孤独 受伤 害怕
- I'm lonely, hurt and scared.
-你的要求“我很害怕”匹配
- Your request "I'm scared" matches
“死亡” “恐惧” “恐怖”
"death", "fear", "horror"...
-伊娃 怎么了？
- Eva, what's going on?
- ... "死亡 恐惧 恐怖
- ... "death", "fear", "horror"...
“孤独而死”
"dying of loneliness".
-大沙？-怎么回事？
- Dasha? - What's happening?
我们不在家
We're not at home.
这不是我们的世界
It's not our world.
我知道我妹妹在哪里
I know where my sister is.
没人需要你
Nobody needs you.
他们会忘记你的
They will forget you.
-上次我在这里看到了什么
- Last time I saw something in here.
在这里
Here.
-你是谁？你有一股很明显的气味
- Who are you? You have a very distinct smell.
-你是谁？-嘘！
- And who are you? - Shh!
安静 宝贝 别哭了！
Hush, baby. Don't cry!
-瓦里亚
- Varya.
这是我妹妹
This is my sister.
-她太小了
- She's so small.
她在女巫的巢穴里哭得那么大声
She cried so loudly in the witch's den.
-什么女巫？
- What witch?
-是她吗？女巫？
- Is it her? The witch?
-没人见过女巫
- Nobody's ever seen the witch.
她不能离开她的巢穴
She can't leave her den.
有可怕的隐形鸟把孩子带到她身边
There are scary invisible birds who bring children to her.
-谁？
- Who?
-他们被称为海军
- They're called the Navs.
他们帮助女巫
They help the witch.
他们能感觉到记忆的味道
They can sense the smell of memories
就像捕食者感觉到血一样
just like predators sense blood.
保持你最明亮的记忆是很重要的
It's important to keep your brightest memory.
只要人们记住我们 我们就一直活着
We remain alive as long as we're remembered.
一旦我们被遗忘 我们就会消失
Once we're forgotten, we disappear.
-什么？
- What?
-看看我
- Look at me.
-你被遗忘了
- You're being forgotten.
-我们应该回到炉子里去
- We should get back to the furnace.
-你不能去那里 你会死的
- You can't go there. You can die.
森林晚上很危险 海军可以抓住你
The forest is dangerous at night the Navs can catch you.
躲起来！
Hide!
别离开避难所 这件斗篷能掩盖你的气味
Don't leave the shelter. The cloak will hide your smell.
嘘 安静！
Shh, quiet!
-嘘 瓦里亚
- Hush, Varya.
-嘿 你要去哪里？
- Hey, where are you going?
-嘿！救命啊！
- Hey! Help!
-嘘 安静 别尖叫
- Shh, quiet. Don't scream.
-嘿 兄弟
- Hey, bro.
她现在要醒了
She is going to wake up now.
-我们必须回家
- We must return home.
把毯子拿走
Take the blanket.
-为什么？
- What for?
-所以他们感觉不到我们的气味
- So they don't sense our smell.
埃戈尔！帮我离开这里
Egor! Help me get out of here.
帮我回来
Help me come back.
-这是什么？那里没有人
- What is it? There's nobody there.
-妈妈？
- Mom?
-嘘！
- Shh!
别害怕
Don't be scared.
你抵抗得越多 他们就越紧张
The more you resist, the stronger they tighten up.
我们可以趁女巫不饿的时候逃走
We can escape while the witch isn't hungry.
那里没有人 走吧！
There's nobody there. Let's go!
-妈妈来电话了
- Mom's calling.
妈妈！
Mom!
妈妈！-埃戈尔！
Mom! - Egor!
-妈妈！-等等！住手！
- Mom! - Wait! Stop!
-埃戈尔？
- Egor?
-瓦里亚
- Varya.
-这不是你第一次来了 是吗？
- This isn't your first time here, is it?
-我已经从这里逃了很多次了
- I've escaped from here many times.
当女巫在吃东西的时候 其他人可以逃走
While the witch is eating, the others can break away.
-你没事吧？
- Are you okay?
-最好不要问！-进炉子里去
- Better not ask! - Go into the furnace.
-那里没有通道 我试过很多次了
- There's no passage there, I've tried it many times.
我们应该回我家去
We should go back to my house.
-等等！
- Wait!
请跟我们来 你爸爸在等你
Please, come with us. Your dad is waiting for you.
我们能做到的
We can make it.
-伙计们 我们得走了
- Guys, we have to go.
-我告诉过你-没有回头路了
- I told you — there's no way back.
-没有
- No.
一定有出路
There must be a way out.
-那是不可能的 除非
- That's impossible. Unless...
一旦你死了
you've already died once.
你就是女巫要找的人
You're the one the witch is looking for.
-蜡烛熄灭了 他忘了我
- The candle went out. He forgot me.
-我们走！快点！
- Let's go! Hurry!
-请保持你最美好的记忆
- Please, keep your brightest memory.
-这东西会回来的 我们该怎么办？
- This thing will come back. What are we going to do?
-我们会想出办法的 好吗？
- We'll come up with something, okay?
-爸爸！朱莉娅！
- Dad! Julia!
-你是谁？你在这里干什么？
- Who are you? What are you doing here?
滚出我的房子 拉格姆芬！出去！
Get out of my house, ragamuffin! Out!
-妈妈！
- Mom!
-是你打碎了我的窗户吗？
- Was that you who broke my window?
-我看见你女儿了 -什么女儿？
- I saw your daughter. - What daughter?
如果我再见到你   走出！
If I see you again... Get out!
-你是谁 小男孩？
- Who are you, little boy?
你怎么进来的？
How did you get in here?
你为什么哭？
Why are you crying?
我想我认识你
I think I know you.
还有一件事…但这是个秘密
And one more thing...But it's a secret.
每天晚上我都会梦到一个哭泣的小女孩
Every night I see this dream about a little crying girl.
然后我醒来
Then I wake up.
我疯了吗？
Am I crazy?
-你能听见吗？
- You can hear her?
朱莉娅 这很严重
Julia, this is very serious.
如果你还记得她
If you remember her,
她还活着
she's still alive.
她叫瓦里亚
Her name is Varya.
你还记得吗？
Do you remember?
-我的小瓦里亚
- My little Varya.
-朱莉娅 我得走了
- Julia, I have to go.
拜托 想想瓦里亚
Please, think of Varya.
-瓦里亚
- Varya...
-真正的男人必须保护他们所爱的人
- Real men must protect those who are dear to them.
爸爸！拜托 住手
Dad! Please, stop.
是我
It's me.
-放开他！
- Let him go!
快跑 埃戈尔 我能对付他
Run, Egor, I can handle him.
亚历克西 记住 那是你儿子！
Alexey, remember, that's your son!
-我不明白发生了什么事
- I don't understand what's going on.
-大家都忘了我们
- Everyone's forgotten us.
-那又怎样？你被遗忘了 但我
- So what? You're forgotten, but I
我一辈子都没注意到
haven't been noticed my whole life.
我看不出有什么不同
I don't see any difference.
你怎么这么瘸？
Why are you being so limp?
我肯定你妹妹还活着
I'm sure your sister's still alive.
我们会回来找她 毁掉火炉
We'll come back for her and destroy the furnace,
这样孩子们就不会再消失了
so the kids won't disappear anymore.
-我们得想办法杀了雅加先生
- We need to figure out how to kill Baba Yaga.
-好的老办法怎么样？
- What about a good old way?
-我们要烧了巫婆！
- We'll burn the witch!
-我会教你闯入我的财产
- I'll teach you to break into my property.
-记住你的女儿
- Remember your daughter.
我们需要你的帮助 你必须记住
We need your help. You have to remember.
-你见过她吗？
- Have you seen her?
你见过我女儿吗？
Have you seen my daughter?
-是的 炉子里有一条通道
- Yes. There's a passage in the furnace.
-但她走了
- But she's gone.
她没能成功
She didn't make it.
-如果她死了我会感觉到的
- I would feel it if she died.
-是的 她走了 我看到了
- It's true, she's gone. I saw it.
-她还活着！
- She's alive!
通道在哪里？
Where's the passage?
-呆在这里 如果我不回来 把所有东西都烧掉
- Stay here. If I don't come back, burn everything down.
-我们都去 一起
- We'll all go. Together.
蜂蜜
Honey.
来找我
Come to me.
蜂蜜
Honey.
-埃戈尔 你怎么这么久才来？
- Egor, what took you so long?
-这不可能是真的
- It can't be true.
你不在这里
You're not here.
-宝贝 你太特别了
- Baby, you're so special.
你可以跨越世界的边界
You can cross the borders of the worlds.
现在我知道了 我们可以一起离开这里
Now I know it. We can leave this place together.
-没有
- No.
-你的朋友忘了你
- Your friends forgot you.
你父亲忘了你
Your father forgot you.
但我爱你
But I love you.
把那个女孩赶走
Get rid of the girl.
把她的生命给我 这样我们就可以再在一起了
Give her life to me, so we can be together again.
-我不想
- I don't want to.
你不是我妈妈 我妈妈死了！
You're not my mother. My mother is dead!
-怎么回事？
- What's happening?
-坦尼娅 记得我！
- Tanya, remember me!
我们的女儿 坦尼娅！我们可以救她
Our daughter, Tanya! We can save her.
-她答应带她回来
- She promised to bring her back...
如果我把男孩带到她身边
if I bring her the boy.
帮我出去
Help me get out.
否则你会死的
Or you will die.
-他的父母也爱他
- He has parents who love him too.
曾经喜欢我们的女儿
Like you used to love our daughter.
-他也有父母
- He has parents too.
真正的男人必须保护他们所爱的人
Real men must protect those who are dear to them.
没人会记得你
No one will remember you.
不 我们记得彼此
No. We remember each other.
在这里！来抓我们！
Over here! Come get us!
你是他们会忘记的人！
You're the one they'll forget!
嘿 你！
Hey you!
-亚历克西 听着
- Alexey, look.
-等等 给我 -够了 放回去
- Wait, give it to me. - That's enough, put it back.
-哦 来吧 -好吧 够了
- Oh, come on. - Right, enough.
-伙计们 住手 我们拍张照片吧
- Guys, stop it. Let's take a photo.
-你不怕你的朋友出来吗？
- Aren't you afraid that your friend will come out?
-你在我身边
- I have you by my side.
-你愿意加入我们吗？
- Would you like to join us?
-一 二 三
- One, two, three.
-天哪 那张脸真难看
- God, that's an ugly face.
来吧
Come.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
-怎么了？
- What's wrong?
她不会被杀的
She can't be killed.
她会回来的
She'll come back.
嘘！
Shhh!